<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="68"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[AREA III



        CURRICULUM AND


              INSTRUCTION






            E. GRADUATION


               REQUIREMENTS]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[SYSTEM – INPUTS AND



           PROCESSES









            S.1.  There  is  a  policy  on



                       graduation requirements.]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[University Academic calendar is posted in the CvSU website

                (https://cvsu.edu.ph/)  and  is  accessible  to  all  faculty,  staff  and
                students]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[IMPLEMENTATION












           I.1. The students are regularly



                      informed of the academic


                      requirements                                    of            their



                      respective courses.]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[The              Students’                       and              Parents’


                          Orientation 2021 was streamed


                          via Facebook Pages.]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Click the link button to view the full documents.








                        Students’ and Parents’ Orientation 2021

                                   Approved Activity Proposal]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[The registrar’s

                                                                  announcements are


                                                                  posted in the

                                                                  Facebook page of


                                                                  the campus.]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Click the link button to view the documents.



             STUDENTS ARE REMINDED OF THEIR ACADEMIC


          REQUIREMENTS DURING STUDENTS' ORIENTATION]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[IMPLEMENTATION












        I.2.  The  College/Academic  Unit


        implements    the  system  for


        student                                returnees                                    and



        transferees                                  to              meet                     the



        residence  and  other  graduation


        requirements.








             Click the link button to view the full documents.



                     Registrar's Manual 2009]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[The following requirements shall be satisfied by the applicants before he/she is
           admitted to the programs offered by respective colleges or campuses.


           Admission of Freshmen students. The following requirements shall be submitted by the
           applicants to the Office of the University Registrar for admission and registration:


             ●    Notice of Admission issued by OSA
             ●    Original copy Form 137 or form 138
             ●    Original Copy of Certification of Good Moral Character
             ●    Results of Medical and Dental Examination


           Admission of Transfer Students. Transfer Students from other schools and
           colleges/universities are required to submit the following:


             ●    Notice of Admission issued by OSA
             ●    Transcript of Records (Together with Description of courses)
             ●    Honorables Dismissal/Transfer Credentials
             ●    Certification of Good Moral Character by the Guidance Counselor/Dean from the

                  last school attended
             ●    NBI or Police clearance

             ●    Results of the interview and evaluation by the college Evaluation Committee


           In case Transcript of Records from the school last attended is not available at the time of
           enrollment Certification of Grades or True Copy of Grades can be accepted by the College
           Registrar and or the university Registrar under temporary status.

           Admission of Foreign students. Foreign students are required to:


             ●    Submit an approved permit to study from the concerned embassy
             ●    Pay a non-refundable student fee of $30.00

             ●    Other Prescribe requirements/documents by the Bureau of Immigration for student
                  Visa
             ●    Submit a Certificate of English Proficiency from the Department of Languages and
                  Humanities


           Shifting to other Programs. Students who intend to shift to another University program
           must  accomplish  a  prescribed  form  for  the  purpose  to  be  approved  by  the  Dean  of  the
           College where they want to shift to: not late than ten (10) working days before the start of
           the regular registration period. A copy of the approved application for shifting should be
           forwarded by the Dean concerned to the University Registrar's Office.


                                               Lifted From the 2009 CvSU Registrar Manual]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[Students pursuing degree programs may be allowed to shift to non-degree programs
          upon approval of their application for shifting.


                 Students  pursuing  non-degree  program  may  be  allowed  to  shift  to  degree  programs
          offered  by  the  College  after  satisfying  the  following  requirements  except  for  ladderized
          programs:


            ●    GPA of 2.0 or better;
            ●    Submission of approved application form and other supporting documents; and
            ●    PAssing the required entrance examination


          Cross  registration.  Cross  Registrants  from  other  educational  institutions  should  have  a
   written permission from their school registrar to be presented by the CvSU registrar. The permit shall
   state the subject(s) and the total number of units the student is allowed to cross-register and that the
   University shall be the venue for the course to be registered.


                 For  courses  with  prerequisites,  the  cross-registrant  shall  be  required  to  present  an
          authenticated proof of equivalency of course and description of the required course.


                 CvSU  students  who  are  planning  to  cross-register  courses  with  other  institutions
          should have a written permit from their College and the University Registrar's.


                 Students  planning  to  cross-register  in  other  University  College  or  campus  shall  be
          allowed only under the following conditions:


            ●    The course(s) to be cross-registered should have exactly the same description as the
                 one  being  offered  in  the  another  college  or  campus  where  the  student  plan  to
                 cross-register;
            ●    Must  have  written  permit  form  their  respective  College  Registrar  and  finally  the
                 University Registrar; and
            ●    Students  are  allowed  to  cross-enroll  a  maximum  of  six(6)  units  only  for  the  entire
                 program.


          Enrollment for Residency
          A  student  who  registered  the  required  six(6)  units  for  thesis  or  its  equivalent  shall  enroll
   another  one  unit,  if  he  fails  to  defend  his  research.  However,  he  shall  only  be  required  to  enroll
   residence  status  if  he  has  successfully  defended  his  research  but  failed  to  submit  the  bound
   manuscript.


                                              Lifted From the 2009 CvSU Registrar Manual]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[and  other  requirements  for  graduation.  Furthermore,  a  student  may  enroll  residency
            under the following conditions.


             1.    Completed  all  the  academic  requirements  and  completing  thesis  manuscript
                   provided  he/she  had  already  enrolled  six  units  and  successfully  defended  the
                   manuscript,  Provided  further,  that  completion  will  be  done  on  the  following
                   semester.
             2.    No academic load but need to complete the grade of “INC” or remove the grade
                   of “4.0” during the term.
             3.    Unfinished OJT or practicum of least ⅙ of the required number of hours services,
                   provided no written report is to be submitted.
             4.    Completing  written  report  or  narrative  report  but  had  finished  the  required
                   practise teaching
             5.    Enrolled  in  ROTC  or  National  Service  Training  Program  (NSTP)  but  no
                   academic load.
             6.    Students who will register to other University for Valid reasons.


            Enrollment for residency shall be made during the scheduled registration period.


     REQUIREMENTS FOR ADMISSION
            FRESHMEN
              ●    Short Brown Envelope
              ●    Notice of Admission
              ●    Original & Photocopy of Card/Form 138
              ●    Original & Photocopy of Good Moral Character

              ●    Original & Photocopy of Result of Medical and Dental Examination
            TRANSFEREE
              ●    Short Brown Envelope
              ●    Notice of Admission(Signed by the Vice President for Academic Affairs)
              ●    Original  &  Photocopy  of  Results  of  Evaluation  from  the  College  Evaluation
                   Committee/College Registrar
              ●    Original & Photocopy of Transcript of Record/Certification of Grades
              ●    Original & Photocopy of Certificate of Transfer/Honorable Dismissal
              ●    Original & Photocopy of Good Moral Character
              ●    Original & Photocopy of Results of Medical and DEntal Examination
              ●    Original  &  Photocopy  of  NBI  Clearance  if  Below  16  years  old  submit  Police

                   Clearance
            OLD STUDENTS RETURNING
              ●    Short Brown Envelope
              ●    Original & Photocopy of Approved Result of Readmission Evaluation

              ●    Original & Photocopy of Result of Medical and Dental Examination
                                                Lifted From the 2009 CvSU Registrar Manual]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[SHIFTEE
               ●    Short Brown Envelope
               ●    Original & Photocopy of Approved Letter of Intent
               ●    Original & Photocopy of Results of Evaluation from the College Evaluation
                    Committee/College Registrar



































































                                                 Lifted From the 2009 CvSU Registrar Manual]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[Figure 2. Procedure Flow Chart for Admission and Regulation of Transferee


             Evaluation of Credentials                             Evaluation of Grades
             Office of Student Affairs                            College of Evaluation
                         (OSA)                                           Committee






          Interview Notice of Admission                           Entrance Examination
        Office of the Vice president for                             Office of Student

                 Academic Affairs                                      Affairs (OSA)










                                                             Submission of Admission
                                                             Requirements Personal information
                                                             for computerized enrollment system
           Medical/Dental Examination                          ●     Student number
                University Infirmary                           ●     Course

                                                               ●     Other information


                                                                      University Registrar







                   Assessment of Fees
                    Registration Form                                      Block Section

                                                                        College Registrar
                  University Registrar





                          Payment
                                                                    Validation of Registration
                                                                    Issuance of Temporary ID
                     Central Student
                   Government (CSG)
                   University Cashier                                 University Registrar

                                                Lifted From the 2009 CvSU Registrar Manual]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[Figure 2. Procedure Flow Chart for Admission and Registration of old Students
   Returning

                                                                         Medical/Dental
         Certificate of Readmission
                                                                           Examination

         University Registrar
                                                                      University Infirmary














                                                            Submission of ReAdmission
                                                            Requirements Personal information
                                                            for computerized enrollment system
                    Block Section
                                                              ●    Student number
                                                              ●    Course
                 College Registrar
                                                              ●    Other information


                                                                     University Registrar






                                                                             Payment
                Assessment of Fees
                  Registration Form
                                                                        Central Student

                                                                      Government (CSG)
                University Registrar
                                                                      University Cashier





                                                                   Validation of Registration
                                                                   Issuance of Temporary ID



                                                                     University Registrar

                                                Lifted From the 2009 CvSU Registrar Manual]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Click the link button to view the documents.


           Policy on Admission and Retention for Undergraduate

       programs and obligation of students who availed RA 10931]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[IMPLEMENTATION













         I.3. Graduating                                                    students



                     conduct  research  and/or


                     undergo  practicum/OJT  or



                     other  activities  prescribed


                     in                   their                        respective



                     curricula.]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[Course in the checklist (new curriculum)]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[Course in the checklist (old curriculum)]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[RESEARCH AS A


                    REQUIREMENT OF



                          THE PROGRAM









              COMPILATION OF STUDENT



                                  RESEARCHES]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[Click the link button to view the documents.






                                 Practicum MOA



                    BS Office Administration







                    Sample Narrative Report






                                  Compilation of


                          Student Researches







                              Sample Research]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[IMPLEMENTATION










        I.4. The  College/department  of



                   Business                                       Management



                   assists                         the                 graduating


                   students                          with                  academic


                   deficiencies,                                     disciplinary



                   cases,  and  other  problems



                   which  hinder  issuance  of


                   clearances.]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[IMPLEMENTATION











              I.5. Clearance                                                    from



                         academic  and  financial


                         accountabilities                                          and



                         responsibilities                                               is


                         required                                          before



                         graduation.]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[OUTCOMES











              O.1.  At  least  60%  of  the



                         students  enrolled    in


                         the  program  are    able



                         to  graduate    within  the


                         regular  time frame.]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[]]></page></pages></Search>